<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rachel Tobin Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://racheltobin.work/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rachel Tobin Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://racheltobin.work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some words here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Demo</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/watchdemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/watchdemo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;description:16bc38f1e5f4b90f5cb7255098f3980a&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, I was tasked with creating an interactive element on our OmniFocus marketing page showcasing the new Apple Watch App. This was prior to the Apple Watch release, so no actual Apple Watches were yet available. Given the simplicity of the watch interface, I decided to do a full demo of our watch app, as if the user were using the real app. In collaboration with a designer, we created all UI elements of the watch app in SVG using Illustrator, and used JavaScript to trigger page changes, simulating the actual app. This was then paired with description tex timed with the page changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-used:16bc38f1e5f4b90f5cb7255098f3980a&#34;&gt;Tools Used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JavaScript and jQuery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SVG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adobe Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omni Group Support Site</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/supportsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/supportsite/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;description:e3c65a75a19e5ee297ad9c7f0e8773fc&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, we wanted to add a knowledge-base like functionality to our previously static-only, FAQ-style product support pages, as well as provide a single location for users to access our manuals on the web. In collaboration with another web developer, we devised a system where support staff could write support articles using Markdown and add them easily to the support site without needing to enlist developer help. In addition to this, we leveraged the Python Whoosh library to make these articles searchable with a search-as-you-type feature. For documentation, we created scripts to read the EPUB documents our documentation team was already producing, and convert them to indexable, web-based documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-used:e3c65a75a19e5ee297ad9c7f0e8773fc&#34;&gt;Tools Used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoosh Search Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backbone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RequireJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omni ID OAuth 2.0 Provider</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/omniid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/omniid/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;description:31a10bfd5d886b6657a04d90ede5f5b7&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Omni ID, we wished to create a single, secure, and predictable login for all of the Omni Group&amp;rsquo;s web services. This involved using the OAuth 2 standard along with the Python oauth-lib library and a custom Django auth backend to create a secure OAuth provider that could authorize users on other valid services either via a username and password or via a token. Myself and another web developer designed this service to allow both web-based clients and native-app clients and for future expansion. Currently, this provider is used for logins to stenciltown2.omnigroup.com service, with future services planned for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-used:31a10bfd5d886b6657a04d90ede5f5b7&#34;&gt;Tools Used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python OAuth 2 Lib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom Django authentication backend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;experience:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;EXPERIENCE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Developer, The Omni Group, Seattle, WA — Nov 2013 - Present&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintained and developed web content across all of the Omni Group’s web presence, including the marketing site, support site, user forums, sync service, internal tools, and other auxiliary sites. Worked with a team of designers for major redesigns, as well as completely new projects developed from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Human,  The Omni Group, Seattle, WA — Apr 2012 - Nov 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provided telephone and email technical support for The Omni Group’s Mac and iOS software applications, and was involved in collecting and categorizing customer feedback for product improvement. Created scripts and customizations for our Request Tracker ticketing system using Perl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genius,  Apple Inc. Roseville, MN &amp;amp; Seattle, WA — Oct 2010 - Apr 2012&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performed technical support for Mac users in a retail environment; repaired hardware and software on Apple computers and mobile devices; administered store Deploy Studio server and diagnostic toolkit server and associated wikis; belonged to a team responsible for maintenance and administration of store use Snow Leopard and Lion servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computer Support Technician, University of Wisconsin, River Falls, WI — Aug 2008 - Sept 2009&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supported a campus of approximately 2,000 computers, using both Mac and Windows OS; responded to technical support requests via Numara Footprints software; administered McAfee ePolicy Orchestrator server and helped develop campus-wide security policy;  developed scripts for improved automation of routine updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;education:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;EDUCATION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of Minnesota, Twin Cities - 2010-2011&lt;/strong&gt; - Completed courses towards Computer Science and Asian Languages majors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shih Hsin University, Taipei, Taiwan - 2009-2010&lt;/strong&gt; - Foreign Exchange Program through University of Wisconsin; completed Mandarin Chinese Language courses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of Wisconsin, River Falls, WI - 2008-2009&lt;/strong&gt; - Completed Computer Science and Japanese Language courses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utsunomiya Joshi Kōkō, Utsunomiya, Japan - 2007-2008&lt;/strong&gt; - Rotary International Exchange Program&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Century College, White Bear Lake, MN - 2006-2007&lt;/strong&gt; - Completed Computer Science courses as a PSEO student&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skills:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;SKILLS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front End:&lt;/strong&gt;
    HTML, CSS, CSS Preprocessors, Javascript, jQuery, Backbone/Underscore, JS       Task Runners, JS Testing, JS Code Quality Tools, SVG and SVG                animation, responsive design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back End:&lt;/strong&gt;
    Python, Django, Flask, RESTful API creation, Relational databases, OAuth,       Apache, FreeBSD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General:&lt;/strong&gt;
    Mac OS X, Subversion, Git, Adobe Illustrator, OmniGraffle for wireframing&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stenciltown</title>
      <link>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/stenciltown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://racheltobin.work/recent-work/stenciltown/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;description:207923ea96c840cd02b3971d47e5db57&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a complete redesign project that added a variety of new features from the original Stenciltown site.
We added user accounts, social features such as &amp;ldquo;likes&amp;rdquo; and user profiles, integration with our new single sign on OAuth 2.0 provider, Omni ID, as well as new API endpoints to allow users to upload stencils directly from within the OmniGraffle app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-used:207923ea96c840cd02b3971d47e5db57&#34;&gt;Tools Used&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SCSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial Backbone Front-end(previous iteration was 100% Backbone front end)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jQuery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OAuth 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python/Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postgresql&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>